<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Palmdrop</title>
    <link>https://palmdrop.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Palmdrop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 14:10:22 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://palmdrop.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Palmdrop.zone - Personal webspace</title>
      <link>https://palmdrop.github.io/post/webspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 14:10:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://palmdrop.github.io/post/webspace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing a personal website from scratch. Although it&amp;rsquo;s not finished yet, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to make it public. Live at &lt;a href=&#34;https://palmdrop.zone&#34;&gt;https://palmdrop.zone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating alien patterns using modified noise and domain warping</title>
      <link>https://palmdrop.github.io/post/alien-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 14:10:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://palmdrop.github.io/post/alien-patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Combining domain warping and modified noise functions can produce extremely detailed and varied alien-like textures and shapes. This post is a peek into how I&amp;rsquo;ve been using these techniques to create pieces of generative art.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast weighted random point generation</title>
      <link>https://palmdrop.github.io/post/fast-weighted-random-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 14:10:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://palmdrop.github.io/post/fast-weighted-random-points/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Generating weighted random points is an essential generative tool. One might use it to generate star clusters, spawn positions, attraction points, and so on. This post will discuss how weighted random point generation can be done efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surfaces - A Recursive Domain Warping Controller</title>
      <link>https://palmdrop.github.io/post/surfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 14:10:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://palmdrop.github.io/post/surfaces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing a web application that provides easy access to the recursive domain warping technique described in previous posts. This app is now live at &lt;a href=&#34;https://palmdrop.github.io/surfaces/&#34;&gt;https://palmdrop.github.io/surfaces/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Characteristics of Modified Noise</title>
      <link>https://palmdrop.github.io/post/characteristics-of-modified-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 20:12:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://palmdrop.github.io/post/characteristics-of-modified-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Regular gradient noise, such as Perlin and Simplex noise, is extremely useful for procedurally generating textures, flowfields, heightmaps, etc. But a texture or heightmap created using plain noise is rarely that interesting. Often, noise is modified or used in unique, creative ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My take on domain warping</title>
      <link>https://palmdrop.github.io/post/domain-warping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 18:25:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://palmdrop.github.io/post/domain-warping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Domain warping: a procedural method for generating natural-looking patterns and shapes. I&amp;rsquo;ve used this technique for a long time, and the results can be beautiful and strangely organic. This post will explore my (slightly different) approach, and some of the images this approached helped produce.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://palmdrop.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://palmdrop.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s quite natural that new technologies and emerging media eventually are used as artistic tools. Digital art has been created for decades, there&amp;rsquo;s been a recent boom in AI art, and there are huge communities of generative artists working with code as their creative medium.
For many years now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using generative/procedural techniques to learn more about programming and digital technologies, and simultaneously to realize my more aesthetic pursuits. I&amp;rsquo;ve experimented with well-known techniques such as domain warping and particle simulations, while also spending time with my own concepts and ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
